Finding Aid for the Ruth St. Denis Papers LSC.1031
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1: Journals, 1900s-1968
  - Journals, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1956-1958 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Journals, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Journals, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Journals, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Journals, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Journals, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Journals, 1932-1953; 1953 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence, references to Harro Meller and the Society of the Divine Dance.
  - Journals, 1941-1955; 1955 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1951 June-1955 Dec; 1955 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence and documents for Creative Arts Guild.
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1951 June-1955 Dec; 1955 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1953 Oct 5-1953 Dec 14 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1953 Oct 5-1953 Dec 14 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Journals (1 of 3), 1953 Dec-1954 Aug (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Journals (2 of 3), 1953 Dec-1954 Aug (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Journals (3 of 3), 1953 Dec-1954 Aug (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1953 Dec 17-1954 Feb 6 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1953 Dec 17-1954 Feb 6 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1954 April 19-1954 Sept 30 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    Includes biographical writings and references to the Hollywood Bowl.
  - Journals, 1910, 1919-1920 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1917, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1920 Jan-1921 Apr, 1925 Dec-1926 Nov (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Includes musical notation.
  - Journals, 1920 Aug-1923 May (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Journals- Orient, 1925 Aug-Dec (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1933, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1944 Aug (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1956, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1938 Mar-1958 April; 1958 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Includes notes for Temple, correspondence, and references to Harro Meller
  - Journals, 1944-1957 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1951-1956 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Includes business notes, articles about Denishawn, and reference to UCLA.
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1951-1956 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Journal entries, 1955 Jan-Feb (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1956 Jan 1-1957 June 3 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Includes biographical writings and notes on "Money Laboratory."
  - Journals, 1956 May 12-1956 June 26 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Includes correspondence and references to William Skipper.
  - Journals, 1956 Aug 11-1956 Sept 16 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1956 Sept 20-1956 Oct 13 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Journal entries, 1956 Nov (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Journal entries, 1957 Jun-1958 Dec (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1957 July (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1957 Dec-1958 Feb (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Journal entries, 1958 Jan (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Journals, 1958 Jan-1958 Dec (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Includes notes for "Evening with Ruth St. Denis," correspondence, and references to William Skipper.
  - Journals, 1958 Feb (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Journals, 1958 July 22-1958 Nov 15 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    Includes prayers, notes for "Gold Madonna," and references to William Skipper.
  - Journals, 1958 July 30-1958 Nov 27 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Journals, 1959 June 10-1959 Sept 12 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    Includes references to William Skipper.
  - Journals, 1958 July 17-1958 July 26 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Journals, 1959 May 8-1959 June 30 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Journals, 1959 Sept-Oct (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Journals, 1960 Aug 4-1960 July 11 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Journals, 1964 Mar 3-1964 April 1 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Journals, 1967 July (Box 23, Folder 25)
    Includes notes for Temple and notes for "Leaflet from B + F Reproduction"
  - Journals, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Includes Virginia and West Virginia journals.
  - Journals, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Includes Montreal and Toronto journals.
  - Journals, 1919-1920 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1924 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1927-1963 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1928 Mar 14 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1928 June-1928 Nov (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1928-1932; 1932 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Includes references to Church of the Divine Dance.
  - Journals, 1932 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Includes notes for "Nehemiah," references to "Babylon."
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1930-1967 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Includes undated tour schedule, notes for Temple and Center for Divine Dance, references to UCLA and William Skipper.
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1930-1967 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1931-1953 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1932-1957 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1932-1957 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1933-1954 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    Includes biographical writings, notes on Colony, and miscellaneous articles.
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1933-1954 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1942 Jan 25 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Journals (1 of 3), 1950 Aug-1951 Oct (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Includes biographical writings and Boston journals.
  - Journals (2 of 3), 1950 Aug-1951 Oct (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Journals (3 of 3), 1950 Aug-1951 Oct (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1953-1956; 1953 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1953 Feb-1954 July (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Journals- "Beginning New Journal", 1956 Oct 13-1956 Oct 29 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1957-1962 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Includes biographical writings, notes for "The Madonna Section" and "The Mind of Light," references to William Skipper, business correspondence, and speeches.
  - Journals, 1963 Sept 19-1963 Dec 5 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1964 Sept 9-1964 Oct 14 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1964 Dec-1965 Aug (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Journals- "January Writings 1967", 1967 Jan (Box 25, Folder 13)
    Includes business notes, references to William Skipper and UCLA, writings by unidentified author.
  - Journals, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Includes references to Temple, Ruth St. Denis Theatre Intime, "White Jade," and "Incense."
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1919-1952 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Includes notes for Colony and Society of the Spiritual Arts.
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1919-1952 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1950 July-1951 Aug (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Includes biographical writings, notes for dances, correspondence, lectures, "The Rule (of St. Denis)."
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1950 July-1951 Aug (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960-1967 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Includes bequests and notes for religious dance series.
  - Journals, 1961 Mar-1965 Mar (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1961 April-1966 Feb (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Includes biographical writings, writings on "The Science of Man."
  - Journal entries, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Journal entries, Sept 1958 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1958-1965 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Journal entries, 1959 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1966 Jan-Feb (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1964 June-July (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1963 April-June (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1964 May-June (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1963 April-May (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1964 Aug-Sept (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1963 July-Aug (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1963 Aug (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1963 Oct (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1964 June-1968 April (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1965 July-August (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1966 February (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1966 March-June (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - "Special Essays '62", 1964 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1964 July (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1964 May (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1964 February (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1966 May (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1965 Nov-Dec (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1968 February (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1963 August (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1963 April (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Journals and notes, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1963 Dec-1964 Jan (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1964 June-July (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1963 October (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1963 March-April (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1964 November (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1965 Sept (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Journals, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1962 Oct-Nov (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1963 Oct (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1963 Nov (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1964 April (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1964 Sept (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1966 Jan-Feb (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1962 May (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1965 March (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1963 April (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1967 April-June (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1967 June (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1962 Dec (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1968 May (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1965 Oct (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Journals- Rosemary, 1964-1965 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1950s-1960s (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1966 Dec (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Journals (1 of 5), 1946 Mar-1966 June; 1965-1966 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Journals (2 of 5), 1946 Mar-1966 June; 1965-1966 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Journals (3 of 5), 1946 Mar-1966 June; 1965-1966 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Journals (4 of 5), 1946 Mar-1966 June; 1965-1966 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Journals (5 of 5), 1946 Mar-1966 June; 1965-1966 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Journals (1 of 3), 1960 April-1966 July; 1965-1966 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Journals (2 of 3), 1960 April-1966 July; 1965-1966 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Journals (3 of 3), 1960 April-1966 July; 1965-1966 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Journals (1 of 4), 1920 Dec-1967 Aug; 1963-1967 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Journals (2 of 4), 1920 Dec-1967 Aug; 1963-1967 (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Journals (3 of 4), 1920 Dec-1967 Aug; 1963-1967 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Journals (4 of 4), 1920 Dec-1967 Aug; 1963-1967 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Journals (1 of 2), 1947 Sept-1968 Mar; 1962-1968 (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - Journals (2 of 2), 1947 Sept-1968 Mar; 1962-1968 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 133, Folder 4)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1963 July-August (Box 133, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1967 Jan-Feb (Box 133, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1966 Nov (Box 133, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 13)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 14)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 15)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 13)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 134, Folder 14)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diary, 1962 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1965 March-April (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1960 Dec-1961 Jan (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1965 August (Box 135, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1965 May-August (Box 135, Folder 9)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1966 May-June (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 137, Folder 7)
  - Journal entries, 1960s (Box 137, Folder 8)
  - Speeches/lectures, 1927 (Box 137, Folder 9)
  - "Ruth St. Denis Enters Third Cycle" by T. Everett Harre, 1930 (Box 137, Folder 10)
  - "General notes on Chromatics" by Daisy M. Huntington, undated (Box 137, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Los Angeles Address Book, undated (Box 137, Folder 12)
  - Journals 1960 March-June, Miscellaneous writing, 1950s-1960s (Box 125, Folder 11)
  - Journals (1 of 4), 1919 Dec - 1949 Dec (Box 117, Folder 1)
    Includes notes for Temple and Church of the Divine Dance and speeches.
  - Journals (2 of 4), 1919 Dec - 1949 Dec (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Journals (3 of 4), 1919 Dec - 1949 Dec (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Journals (4 of 4), 1919 Dec - 1949 Dec (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Journal, London, 1936 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Journal entries, 1956 Sept-Dec (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1956 Dec (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1957 Jan-1957 Feb (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1959 Jun-1960 Aug (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1953 April-1953 May (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1966 Dec (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Journal entries, 1967 July-Aug (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1950s (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1950s (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1952 July-Oct (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1952-1953; 1953 (Box 118, Folder 4)
    Includes notes on Temple, "Wisdom of the Ages," and "Ministry of Beauty" writings.
  - Journals, 1952 June 3-1952 July 26 (Box 118, Folder 5)
    Includes notes for Temple, dance notes, and sketches.
  - Journals, 1952 Nov 11-1952 Dec 4 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    Includes notes for "Divine Dance."
  - Journals, 1952 Dec 21 (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1953 July 16-1953 Aug 19 (Box 118, Folder 8)
    Includes correspondence and references to Light of Asia and the Divine Dance.
  - Journals, 1953 Aug 27-1953 Oct 12 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 8)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 119, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1920s-1940s (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Charcoal journals, 1930-1967 (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - Journal entries, 1950s (Box 131, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1956 May-June (Box 131, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1956-1957 (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1957 Jan-Mar (Box 131, Folder 11)
  - Journals, 1930s-1940s (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1950s (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1950s (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1957-1958 (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1958 (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1958-1959 (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous journals, 1959 Jan-Sept (Box 132, Folder 7)
  - Journals, 1959 July-Aug (Box 132, Folder 8)
  - Journals, 1959 Oct (Box 132, Folder 9)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 132, Folder 10)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Journals, undated (Box 152, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 152, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 152, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 152, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 1960s (Box 152, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1951-1956 (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1956-1957 (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - Journals, undated (Box 153, Folder 3)
  - Journals, undated (Box 153, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1886-1968
  The correspondence series contains letters written from the 1890s and 1968 between St. Denis and friends, family, business partners, members of her studio, and students. Some of the letters St. Denis sent were newsletters she sent to her friends and family to keep them up to date on her life. This series also contains greeting cards sent to St. Denis from friends, family, and students, as well as contact lists.
  - Subseries 2.1: Lists of contacts, 1920s-1960s
    Consists of lists of contact information for St. Denis's colleagues, students, and members of St. Denis's various organizations.
    - Lists of contacts, 1920s-1950s (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Lists of contacts, 1940s-1960s (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Lists of contacts, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Address Book, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles address book, undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Contacts, undated (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - "Special list compiled for Adelphi College", 1911 February (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - Adelphi College donor information, 1962 (Box 125, Folder 16)
    - Contact lists, undated (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - Contact lists, undated (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - Contacts, undated (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Contact lists, 1940s-1950s (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Contacts, 1936 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - Contact lists for Society of Spiritual Arts, undated (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - List of Denishawn students, 1924-1930 (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2.2: Greeting cards, 1950s-1960s
    Consists of greeting cards sent to St. Denis, mainly around Christmas or her birthday. The cards are mainly from her friends and family, as well as many of her students.
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1966-1967 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1967 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards (1 of 2), 1965-1966 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards (2 of 2), 1965-1966 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1957-1966 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1964-1965 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1964-1965 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1961-1967 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1954-1967 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1963-1964 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1965-1968 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1961-1967 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, 1966 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Greeting cards, undated (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2.3: Correspondence, 1886-1968
    Consists of letters written to and from St. Denis and Ted Shawn, Pearl Wheeler, William Skipper, as well as her students, members of her organizations, and business associates. These letters discuss such topics as performances, choreography, travel, personal, fundraising, and other business matters.
    - 1886-1899, Dennis, Ruth Emma Hull; Denis, Thomas Laban (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Handwritten letters primarily between Ruth, her mother Ruth Emma Hull Dennis, and her father Thomas Laban Denis.
    - 1900 February-May, Dennis, Ruth Emma Hull; Denis, Thomas Laban (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Compilation of letters by Ruth to her parents Ruth Emma Hull Dennis and Thomas Laban Denis. Letters primarily sent during her trip to London.
    - 1900-1901, Dennis, Ruth Emma Hull; Denis, Thomas Laban (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Handwritten letters by Ruth to her parents Ruth Emma Hull Dennis and Thomas Laban Denis.
    - 1901-1902, Dennis, Ruth Emma Hull; Denis, Thomas Laban; St. Denis, Brother (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Handwritten letters primarily between Ruth, her mother Ruth Emma Hull Dennis, her father Thomas Laban Denis, and her brother Buzz Dennis, also known as Brother St. Denis.